365online.com 2019-09-02

# Privacy Statement - Bank of Ireland Group Website

Bank of Ireland Group is committed to keeping your information private. We understand that your privacy and the security of your information are very important to you.

#### Terms and Conditions

Bank of Ireland Group’s Privacy Statement is subject to the Terms and Conditions of Use of your Bank of Ireland Group products and services.

We recommend that you read your Terms and Conditions of Use. If there is a conflict between your Terms and Conditions of Use and this Privacy Statement, your Terms and Conditions of Use shall prevail. Except as otherwise provided, terms used herein and defined in your Terms and Conditions of Use shall have the same meaning that is given to them in the Terms and Conditions of Use.

#### Information We Collect From Your Use of Our Website

Our aim is to continuously improve your experience of our digital channels. We use cookies to improve your customer experience of our products, service and online applications. Our web server collects information about your visit, for example:

  * number of people who visit the website;
  * date and time of visits;
  * number of pages viewed;
  * amount of time spent on the website;
  * popular sections of the website.

We may also collect information that you provide such as where you enter details into our website for the purpose of making calculations on lending products or for other reasons. Where you do so, we may combine this information with Targeting Cookies to represent this information to you and advertising that is relevant to you. We describe more about how our Targeting Cookies work below.

Subject to your device settings and consents, we may also collect information about your device, your location and whether or not you are a user of Bank of Ireland Digital Banking.  
This information is anonymous and no attempt is or will be made to identify visitors.

#### Location Enabled Services

In certain circumstances our location enabled services require your location to function and if you wish to use such features you will be asked to consent to your data being used for this purpose. This consent may be withdrawn at any time.

#### Personal Information You Provide To Us

Any information gathered in respect of transactions on your accounts is retained by Bank of Ireland Group solely for the purpose of operating your account.

We only ask for personal information when applying for e.g. a credit card, mortgage or personal loan. All information provided to us by you will be treated with the utmost confidentiality in accordance with all applicable legislative and regulatory standards.

If you ever decide that you no longer wish us to keep or use information or you want the information to be revised or updated, please feel free to contact us. We will remove or amend the information as appropriate in accordance with applicable legislative and regulatory requirements.

#### ‘Cookies’

Cookies are used to monitor website traffic and enhance your experience of our website. Cookies are pieces of data which your computer, mobile or tablet device downloads when you visit a website. Cookies are used to keep track of your preferences and to recognise return visitors.  
You can set your browser to reject cookies. However, if you choose to reject cookies, you may not be able to use or access certain of our online or mobile services.

#### Cookie Types

**Necessary**

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around websites and use the websites’ features, such as accessing secure websites or secure areas of websites. Without these cookies, services you have asked for, like online banking and mobile banking, cannot be provided.

**Functional**

These cookies allow Bank of Ireland Group’s websites to remember choices you make (such as your preferred language) and provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customise. They may also be used to provide services you have asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. Other examples include cookies that keep track of your progress when filling online application forms.

**Performance**

These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don’t collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. Bank of Ireland Group uses first-party analytics cookies for this purpose.

**Targeting Cookies**

Targeting cookies remember individual websites you have visited and help Bank of Ireland to present relevant and targeted online advertising to you. Targeting cookies may be placed on your machine when you visit a Bank of Ireland Group website page. When targeting cookies have been placed on your device, they can be recognised by subsequent websites you visit, and this allows those sites to present targeted Bank of Ireland Group and third party advertising to you. While targeting cookies can track your visits around different websites and identify if you are a user of Bank of Ireland Digital Banking, the information collected is anonymous.

For more information on ‘Cookies’ please click here.

#### Use of Digital Banking and Cookies

Bank of Ireland Digital Banking 365 Online, Mobile and Tablet apps, (which for the purposes of this Privacy Statement also includes Business On Line and any other Bank of Ireland Digital Banking Channel) requires the use of certain functional cookies. By using any of the Bank’s Digital Banking channels, you consent to the use of cookies and collection of data. If you choose to block cookies, you may not be able to use or access certain of our online or mobile services.

#### Digital Banking – Use of Information when Logging On

When you log into Bank of Ireland Digital Banking we will collect information about you and your use of our services. For example we will be able to identify you as a customer, what pages you navigate to and your actions while logged in. This helps us to optimise the service Bank of Ireland provides to you, deliver relevant communications to you and allows you to get the most out of your Bank. By using any of Bank of Ireland’s Digital Banking channels, you consent to the collection of this type of personally identifiable information and use of this information for these purposes.

#### Push Notifications on the Mobile Banking App

Push notifications are messages that mobile apps send to your mobile device to improve your interaction and experience with us. You may receive notifications about services, offers and product information based on your location and your preferences. Upon download or upgrade of the mobile banking app you will be asked for permission to switch on location and notification services. You can decline either or both of these permissions. To get the most out of your notifications you can turn on Bluetooth. You can control your push notification, location and Bluetooth and settings directly on your mobile device.

#### Disclosure of information

We will not divulge your customer information to a third party unless we have received customer authorisation OR we are required to do so by law.

#### Security of information

We understand the importance of security and the confidentiality of your information is to you. Keeping your information secure is a top priority for Bank of Ireland Group. Our goal is to protect your information on the Internet in the same way as we would over the phone, in a branch or at an ATM. Even so, Bank of Ireland Group cannot guarantee the privacy or confidentiality of information relating to you passing over the Internet.

By using any of the services/information available on or via our websites or apps, you accept and are deemed to accept that electronic mail messaging and Internet communication may not be free from interference by third parties and may not remain confidential. The use by you of our websites or apps is at your sole risk.

Learn more about what you can do to protect yourself online.

#### Disclaimer

No member of the Bank of Ireland Group or any of its agents or employees accepts any liability for any loss or damage of any nature, including but not limited to loss of profits, goodwill, or any other type of financial or other pecuniary or direct or special indirect or consequential loss howsoever arising whether in negligence or for breach of contract or other duty, arising out of or in relation to the use and/or dissemination of personal information relating to you where such use and/or dissemination of information is done in accordance with this Privacy Statement and the Terms and Conditions of Use (in the event of conflict the Terms and Conditions of Use shall prevail).

#### How you can protect yourself:

  * Never reveal your password to anyone
  * Never give your full PIN or login details to anyone who calls you or in an email or by text message
  * Never login to any Digital Banking channel through a link in an email
  * Only download Bank of Ireland Apps from official sources (i.e. Apple App Store and Google Play)
  * Lock your phone or tablet when inactive
  * Monitor your accounts, credit card and your list of online payees on a regular basis to ensure everything is in order. One of the best ways to detect fraudulent activity quickly is by examining your account activity regularly. Check for suspicious money transfers, payments or unauthorised access.

If you do find anything suspicious, report it. 

  * 365 online displays your last login and last payee added details, check this is correct.
  * Always logout of 365 online, Bank of Ireland Mobile and Tablet app., Business On Line or any Bank of Ireland Digital Banking Channel.

Learn more about what you can do to protect yourself online.

#### Fraud

A number of banking organisations and their customers has been the target of hoax e-mails that are aimed at gathering Internet/account details of the customers. Some of these hoax e-mails have encouraged or facilitated contact with hoax websites that purport to be (but are not) the website of the relevant banking organisation. To date the occurrence of such online fraud has not been extensive. The Bank of Ireland Mobile Tablet Banking Apps will only ever be available to download from the Apple App Store or Google Play. However, always be cautious of disclosing your personal details.

We only request your personal details if:

  * You initiate e-mail contact with us; or
  * You initiate a request for a particular service online and we require personal details to provide you with the requested service e.g. a loan or credit card application or other product information. 

#### Hyperlinks

Some of the pages on our websites and/or Digital Banking Channels may contain hypertext links to websites not maintained by Bank of Ireland Group. You are reminded that different terms and conditions of use will apply as a user of such websites. In addition, such websites may not attain the same privacy standards that Bank of Ireland Group maintains.

#### Updates

The contents of this Privacy Statement may change without notice from time to time.
